ipost.com 2014-06-26

# Privacy Policy | Direct Email Marketing Services | Email Marketing Solution | iPost

The personal privacy of Internet users is extremely important to iPost and we recognize and support the protection of clients’ and consumers’ privacy rights as a fundamental principle of our business.

**Information Collection and Use**

iPost does not sell, share, or rent mailing lists. We deliver messages only to those addresses supplied to the iPost service by the organization or individual who desires to send a message. That means that if you receive a message from iPost, the sender of that message knows that you are receiving it. iPost also requires its clients to provide accurate information that fully identifies the sender, and verifies that information before accepting email addresses from that sender. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

In the process of delivering email messages, iPost recognizes any URLs that were clicked and records some information supplied by your computer, such as the type of browser, operating system and IP address. We do not use “cookies” to identify users or to measure mailing effectiveness. Information regarding activity for email recipients is reported only to the mailing originator, who owns or has a suitable license to the list on which the recipient’s email address originally appeared.

Although more than one sender may independently supply your address, your name, email address, zip code or other identifying information, such information given to us by one sender will not be revealed to any other sender who uses our service. Should we ever change our policy, you will be notified by email and given the chance to remove yourself from our lists before your information is disclosed.

Users of our website are notified on the website when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether they should proceed with services that require an outside party. At present, no third parties collect information on our website.

**Unsolicited Commercial Email (UCE) Policy**

iPost contractually prohibits our clients from sending email that fits the definition of unsolicited commercial email or “spam.” The term “spam” refers to emailing a message to address(es) that have not asked to receive it. iPost strictly enforces this policy. We insist that our clients send messages with iPost only to recipients who have subscribed, indicating that they wish to receive mailings from our client. In addition, every message sent using the iPost service provides information about unsubscribing from (that is, choosing not to receive) future mailings.

Our UCE policy is rigorously enforced. iPost may terminate service or take any other action against a client who violates this policy. We encourage recipients and others to report violators. If you believe you have received an email in violation of this policy, please send a message to[privacy@ipost.com](mailto:privacy@ipost.com).

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file stored on a web browser user’s hard drive containing information that is placed there by a website. This information is often used to track visits by the same web browser to the same site, or to remember information between sessions on the website for the convenience of the user.

iPost presently uses a third party web analytics system which uses cookies on this website and the iPost Mailing Manager. These cookies are used only to identify the popularity of web pages and the path visitors take through our site. Visitor identity is not collected or used.

Clients of iPost may elect to use cookies on their own websites, some portions of which may be hosted on iPost servers. iPost is not responsible for the use of such cookies and may have no information about them. If you are concerned about the use of cookies in your web browser, you may adjust the settings of your web browser to selectively accept cookies or reject them entirely.

The iPost Mailing Manager (iMM) website, a part of the iPost service, also uses cookies to permit our clients to more easily log in to the iMM from other services. This use of cookies is optional on the part of our clients.

**Log Files**

We may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer our service, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Tracking pixels**

Tracking pixels (also known as “web bugs”) are small, typically transparent images on a web page that have special names which permit the loading of the web page to be tracked by a web server. iPost does not use tracking pixels on our web site. We do use tracking pixels in HTML email we send to detect when the email is opened. Some of our clients may use tracking pixels on forms that we host on our web servers, and some of those tracking pixels may be linked to tracking services hosted by third parties. Please see our clients’ and the third parties’ privacy policies for information about such tracking pixels.

**Sharing**

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners. Shared aggregated information is not linked to any information about any individual person.

We may partner with another party to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we may share names and other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. Any such partnership activity will also comply with this privacy statement.

**Links**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that iPost is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware of when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected, and services provided, by our web site.

**Newsletter**

From time to time we may offer users the opportunity to subscribe to one of our newsletters. If a user wishes to subscribe to a newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. We only send our newsletters to people who ask to receive them.

**Forms and Surveys**

From time to time we may request information from users via forms or surveys. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and email address), and demographic information (such as zip code and profession). Contact information will be used to notify the user requesting a quote or other service. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving this site and our services.

**Security**

This website ([www.ipost.com](http://www.ipost.com/ "www.ipost.com")) does not collect highly sensitive information (such as credit card numbers or Social Security numbers) from our users. For information about security on our client-only service site, see the iPost Mailing Manager ASP Site section below.

**Unsubscribing/Updating Personal Information**

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as the zipcode), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data provided to us.

Every message the iPost service sends contains instructions that allow you unsubscribe from messages sent via iPost from the sender of that particular message. iPost notifies our clients of unsubscribe requests, and we permanently retain and respects such requests in our own database.

To contact iPost to request removal from future iPost email communications from any or all senders, you can do one of the following:

  1. Send email to [optout@ipost.com](mailto:optout@ipost.com) specifying the address that you wish to unsubscribe, or
  2. Send mail to the US postal address:  
iPost  
Attn: iPost Optout  
899 Northgate Drive   
Suite 200   
San Rafael, CA 94903
  3. Call one of the following numbers:  
1-415-382-4000 (if you’re outside USA) or  
1-877-934-7678 (if you’re within USA).

**iPost Mailing Manager (iMM) Site**

This site ([www.ipost.com](http://www.ipost.com/ "www.ipost.com")) contains a link to the iPost Mailing Manager (iMM) site. The iMM site is not a consumer site, and may only be accessed by iPost clients with passwords. By using the ASP site, clients are bound by rules and regulations found in their Service Agreement which includes content and privacy regulations for any mailing performed with the iPost service.

The iMM website takes every reasonable precaution to protect our clients’ and email recipients’ information. When users submit information via the website, that information is protected both online and offline. When the iMM site asks users to enter sensitive information or displays sensitive information, that information is encrypted and is protected with the standard SSL security protocol. While on an SSL-secured page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked.

While we use SSL encryption on the iMM site to protect sensitive information online, we also take reasonable measures to protect user information offline. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, all employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [privacy@ipost.com](mailto:privacy@ipost.com).

**Notification of Changes**

If we materially change our privacy policy, we will post a notice on our web site’s homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

You can review the most current version of the Privacy Policy at any time by clicking the Privacy Policy link on the iPost website. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact [privacy@ipost.com](mailto:privacy@ipost.com).
